Guide to the David Gordon papers,1960-1990.
Gordon David, Papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
David Gordon papers, 1960-1990.
6683
David M. Gordon
10 cubic ft.
Correspondence,Publications,Research Materials,Newspapers,Legal Documents,Printed Materials,Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, publications, memos, and subject files concerning his work at The New School in the Bernard Schwartz Center for Economic Policy Analysis and with the Union for Radical Political Economics (URPE).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Economics at The New School for Social Research.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, publications, memos, and subject files concerning his work at The New School in the Bernard Schwartz Center for Economic Policy Analysis and with the Union for Radical Political Economics (URPE).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Gordon, David M.; New School University.Economics Dept.; New School University.Center for Economic Policy Analysis.; Union for Radical Political Economics.
Subjects:
Economics.; Radicalism.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Collection closed for processing.
CONTAINER LIST
- David Gordon Harvard Class Notes and Exams
- Harvard Class Notes EC 233 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Harvard Class Notes Gerschenknon (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 201 Part I, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 201 Part II, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 221, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 251, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 284 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 296 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 174 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 275 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 274, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 202, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 201 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 202 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Harvard Class Notes EC 201 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Economic Theory Notes for General Exams (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Final Exams, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Urban Economics Notes for General Exams (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Econometrics Notes for General Exams (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Public Finance Notes for General Exams (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Thesis Related Materials
- France joins the common market Part I, April 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- France joins the common market Part II, April 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Essays of David Gordon and others
- The Urban Problem Of The Sixteenth Century, January 1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence and Comments (Box 1, Folder 21)
- The Threat Of Expansion, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Isolation Of The Ghetto From Suburban Employment, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- To the People of the People's Republic of China, August 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Diary of the Chinese People's Republic, August 1972 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Various Articles by Gordon, 1986,1998.1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- American Poverty, April 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Various Articles by Gordon (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Twisted Dream, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Review of Race and Economics, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Homogenise, Divide and Rule: By Nolan and Edwards, December 1982 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Putting The Horse Before The Cart, July 1991 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Growth, Distribution and The Rules Of The Game, June 1993 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Socialism: Whats Left After The Collapse Of The Soviet System, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- A Booming Economy (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Free Trade vs Protectionism: The Wrong Debate (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Sound Spirit, Sound Economy (Box 7, Folder 22)
- What Makes Epochs? (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Strikes And Earnings In Steel, January 1974 (Box 10, Folder 33)
- Segmented Work, Divided Workers (Box 10, Folder 39)
- Papers and Publications
- Papers related to Urban Negro Unemployment, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Original Outline for "Beyond The Waste Land" (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Class and Segementation in the US: A Methodological Review (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Original Notes for "Beyond The Waste Land", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- The Best Defense Is A Good Defense: Toward a Marxian Theory of Labor Union Structure and Behavior, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Capitalist Development and the History of American Cities, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Revised: "Beyond The Waste Land", 1990 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Right Wing Economics: The Anatomy Of Failure (Box 2, Folder 1)
- A democratic economy for the year 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- A Democratic Alternative to Conservative Economics, November 1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Articles from various publications on "Capitalism" (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Tracing The Transition From the "Drive System" to "Capital Labor Accord", October 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Work of Bennett Harrison: Stagnation or Restructuring?, April 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Various magazine and publications (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Work of Fair and Alexander: A Comparison of the Michigan and Fair Models, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Outline for the Cold Bath Paper, August 1986 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Work of Emma Rothschild: Science and Technology in the New Economic Context, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Hiding and Spatially Dividing Workers: Capitalist Development and History of American Cities, November 1976 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Work of Norton: City Lifestyles and Metropolitan Fiscal Structures, A working bibliography, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- A Social Model For Aggregate Productivity of Growth in the US- Actual Publication (Box 2, Folder 30)
- A Social Model For Aggregate Productivity of Growth in the US- Draft, February 1983 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- A Social Model For Aggregate Productivity of Growth in the US- Draft, December 1982 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Taxation Of The Poor And The Normative Theory Of Tax Incidence, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Hearts and Minds: A Social Model (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Various Publications Of Gordon, 1970s,1980s (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Work of Brenner and Glick: The Regulation Approach: Theory and History (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Critique: US Decline in the International Crisis, October 1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Various Articles in NYTimes, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Article in the New Left Review, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Do US Labor Unions Have A Future?, January 1991 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Work of Malgrange and Muet (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Work related to Brenner, 1993,1994 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Levelling The Hills And Valleys: Moving From Uneven To Even Economic Development, march 1976 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Counting The Underemployed, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Work of Phelps: Seven Schools of Macroeconomic Thought, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Draft:"Political Management of Urban Fiscal Crisis", October 1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Can We Pay The Piper? Linkages Between Macroeconomy and Welfare State, October 1987 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Who's Afraid Of The Deficit?, June 1984 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Who Bosses Whom?, December 1989 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Problems in Political Economy (Box 6, Folder 5)
- The Un-Natural Rate Of Employment, December 1987 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Six Percent Unemployment Ain't Natural, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- NYU Conference Paper: "Laying Theory In Concrete", September 1988 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Venice Conference: "Economics For A New Europe", November 1990 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Inferences About The Characteristics Of Missing Males (Box 6, Folder 27)
- A Portfolio Model Of Ghetto Labor Market, April 1968 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Class And The Economics Of Crime Business, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Capitalistic Efficiency And Socialistic Efficiency-Monthly Review, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Draft:" Robin Hood Was Right-Economic Inequality, Insecurity, Crime And Disorder", 1979 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Social Control And Capitalist Cities: A Comment, March 1979 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Hearts and Minds: A Social Model For US Productivity Growth, October 1983 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- The Nation- Up From The Ashes, January-February 1985 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Can We Pay The Piper? Linkages Between Macroeconomy and Welfare State, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Do We Need To Be No.1?, April 1986 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- The Nation- Democratic Economics: "Austerity vs Jobs and Justice", April 1988 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Kaldor's Macro-System, October 1988 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Brussels Conference: "Inside and Outside The Long Swing", May 1989 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Barcelona Conference: "The Economic Crisis in The US", April 1988 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Siena Conference: "International Workshop On Technological and Social Factors in Long Term Fluctuations", December 1986 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Power and Profits, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Power, Accumulation And Crisis, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Politics And Precision: Pursuing Politics Outside The Mainstream, January 1995 (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Paper by ILER: "An Activating Approach To Labor Education", Summer 1979 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Business Ascendancy and Economic Impasse: A Structural Retrospective on Conservative Economics, June 1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Productivity and Workers, August 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Left, Right And Center: An Introdution To Political Economy, December 1987 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Global Economy: Global Edifice Or Crumbling Foundations?, March/April 1988 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Hearts and Minds: A Social Model For US Productivity Growth, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- The Best Defense Is A Good Defense, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Work Of Kaldor: Economics Without Equilibrium, October 1983 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Kaldors' Macro System: Too Much Cumulation, Too Little Disaccumulation, October 1987 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Wageless Recovery, Wageless Growth, January 1994 (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Power, Profits And Investment, January 1993 (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Rising Inequality In US, March 1995 (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Really Putting People First !, January 1993 (Box 7, Folder 57)
- Clintonomics: A Glass Half Empty, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 61)
- The Critique Of Capitalopolis, Fall 1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Capitalist Development and History Of American Cities, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Business Ascendancy And Economic Impasse, Winter 1989 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Who Bosses Whom?, December 1990 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- What Makes Epochs?, December 1986 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- What Makes Epochs?, December 1986 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Work Of Niamh Reilly: A Survey Of Foundation Grant Making In The Area Of Economic Policy Since 1985, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Who Bosses Whom?, December 1990 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Must We Save Our Way Out Of Stagnation?, March 1994 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Bosses Of Different Stripes, January 1994 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Conflict And Co-operation, October 1995 (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Price Inertia And Policy Ineffectiveness in US, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Hiding And Spatially Dividing Workers, November 1976 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Hiding And Spatially Dividing Workers, November 1976 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Capitalism, Class And Crime In America, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Capitalism And Roots Of Urban Crisis, June 1976 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Two Views Of Capitalist Stagnation: Underconsumption And Challenges To Capitalist Control, June 1985 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Income And Welfare In NYC (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Economic Policy In The Keynesian Age: An Alternative To Zero Sum Economics, October 1984 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Work Of Fred Moseley: Estimating The Intensity Of Labor, December 1984 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Reply On Challenge To "Social Model For US Productivity Growth", 1984 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Final Draft: Income And Welfare in NYC, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Draft: "From Steam Whistles To Coffee Breaks", September 1971 (Box 10, Folder 42)
- General
- 25th Reunion (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Graduate School (Box 1, Folder 29)
- New School Appointment, 1973-1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Graduate School Records, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Radical Economists (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Miscellanous Notes (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Occupation Segregation (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Data Correspondence for Labor Market Segmentation (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Labor Segementation Codes (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Publishing Agreement (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Publishers, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- After the Waste Land Bus, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- SHARP Instructions (Box 1, Folder 45)
- MFU in Cities 19th century (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Theory Of labor Unions (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Analysis and Statistics on labor, strikes etc` (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Statistics related to Growth and GNP (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Statistics on Investment (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Statistics on US Labor (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Fair Porke Program User's Guide, October 1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Statistics (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Steps for getting Phd Dissertation Approval (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Statistics of Post-War Growth (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Baseball Players' Statistics (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Baseball Team Predictions and Statistics (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Baseball players and statistics (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Materials related to Urban Economic Growth (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Labor costs and impact on economy (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Statistics on US Population and its relation to economic growth and expansion, 1870-1950 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- The Brookings Institute Economics Studies Program, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- ABCD AEP Study Data Summaries and Worksheets, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Includes program referral and placements
- CEPA Materials (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Papers related to reconstitution of the Graduate Faculty at New School, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Article in "Not So Good Times" about Sam Bowles 's 50th Birthday, June 1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Papers related to French American Foundation, 1989,1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Papers related to Hymer Memorial Fund, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- CVs of David Gordon in 1991, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Resumes of David Gordon (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Some personal files of Gordon, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Institute for Policy Studies Materials, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Personal notes of Rick and Mike Gordon (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Papers related to China trip of 1972, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Journal of Economics Literature (JEL) Review of Vogel, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Systemic Crisis and US Decline (Box 3, Folder 28)
- JEL Related Papers, July 1984 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Editorial Opinions on Unions in NYTimes (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Workplace Accidents: Worse Than War Time?, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Editorial Opinions in NYTimes, July 1974 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Editorial Opinions in NYTimes, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Graduate Faculty Seminars, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Papers related to Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Papers related to CHANGE: Science and University Affairs, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Papers related to National Conference on Social Welfare, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Papers related to Workweek Testimony, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- American Economic Review Session, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- American Economic Review papers, 1980,1981 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Papers related to Quebec Conference, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- WBAI: Letters on the Radio Show, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Hymer Book Materials, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Article in the Shinano Mainichi (Box 3, Folder 46)
- New Management Materials, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Materials related to Cities and Social Control, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Materials related to Marxism and Megalopolis, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Papers related to College For Human Services, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Materials related to Class War in Washingotn Post, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Articles related to Washington Post mobility, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Materials related to Social Research, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- MR Folder on Advanced Capitalism, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Commentary in the Boston Globe, November 1987 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Notes on Investment Paper, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Notes on Investment Paper: Bowles and Weisskopf, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- IAS Seminar, January 1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- The David Gordon Library: Main Catalogue By Author (Box 4, Folder 13)
- The David Gordon Library: Main Catalogue By Title (Box 4, Folder 14)
- The David Gordon Library: Reference Book Catalogue (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Speaking, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Speaking, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Speaking- European, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- The Economic Policy Institute's Conference on Saving and Investment, April 1994 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Real Utopias Project Conference on Equality and Efficiency, Fall 1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Newspaper Articles and Interviews, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Media Book Reviews: "Beyond The Waste Land", 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Reviews: "Beyond The Waste Land", 1983-1991 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- AAAS Program- NSF Chautauqa Type Short Courses, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- AEA Allied Social Science Association's Annual Meeting Session (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Pictures (Box 4, Folder 26)
- NBER Business, 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- URPE Business, 1968-1973 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- National Conference on Social Welfare, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Reviews:"After The Waste Land", 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- NACLA Board, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- NBER OEO Project, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Cambridge Journal OF Economics, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Requests/Permissions to Reprint (Box 4, Folder 36)
- IAS Princeton, NJ Membership (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Yale Daily News Correction, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- LA Times Columns (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Letters: "Recession Is Capitalism As Usual", 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Labor Market Segmentation Permissions, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Labor Market Segmentation Toronto Papers, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Invites for Conference on "Market Segmentation", 1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Papers related to URPE Finances (Box 5, Folder 7)
- URPE Business, 1984,1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- URPE Received mailings, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Papers related to Courier's debt, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Papers related to Southern Courier Fund Raising (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Papers related to "Segementation By The Numbers", 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- URPE ASSA Program (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Final Contract: Labor Market Stratification Project, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Draft and Notes for Proposal: Labor market Stratification Project, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Shelter Island Conference Details, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Papers related to Harlem vs SouthSide (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Draft and Comments: "Recession is Capitalism as Usual", 1975 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Articles, Reviews, Letters related to "Recession is Capitalism as Usual", 1975 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Promotion of :"Whats Wrong With US Economy?A Guide For Working People", 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Papers related to AEA Committee on "Political Discrimination", 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Resolutions about South Africa at AEA Meetings, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Yale Course Meetings (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Yale Course Readings (Box 5, Folder 28)
- URPE Conference on Urban Problems, December 1971 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Deficit Price: Notes and Numbers (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Various Articles of Gordon, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Various Newspaper Articles, 1980s,1990s (Box 5, Folder 38)
- "Problems In Political Economy: An Urban Perspective"- Bibliography and Substantive Notes (Box 6, Folder 3)
- CDA- Proposal and Budget Materials (Box 6, Folder 7)
- CDA- Proposal and Budget Materials II (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Speaking, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Villers Foundation (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Communtites Project (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Citizen Action Economic Program (Box 6, Folder 14)
- CDA Fiscal History (Box 6, Folder 15)
- ILER Finances (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Seminar - School of Social Science Institue for Advance Science, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- CDA Newsletters, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- CDA Peace Project (Box 6, Folder 19)
- CDA Minorities Project (Box 6, Folder 20)
- CDA Worker Policy Project (Box 6, Folder 21)
- CDA Women's Education program (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Research Proposal to Twentieth Century Fund: "US Labor Unions In Transition" (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Data: Who Bosses Whom? (Box 6, Folder 24)
- "After The Waste Land" - Figures and Graphs (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Reply To Bruce Norton's "The Power Axis" (Box 6, Folder 46)
- US Dept. Of Labor: R equest for Proposal, July 1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Financial Statements, August 1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Papers related to ILER, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- List of tasks, meetings, workshops at ILER proposed for coming year, October 1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Papers related to ILER, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Description and other details of "The End Of The American Century" (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Papers related to proposals for ILER, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- LA Times Communication Protocol (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Papers related to Labor Institute, March 1984 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Newsletters (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Papers for a small research project, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Papers related to AEA Natural Rate (Box 7, Folder 18)
- CDA Survey Project, 1980s,1990s (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Various Newspaper Articles (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Photocopies Of Various Newspaper Articles (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Statistics for "Deteriorating Performance of Post War Economy", 1940-1990 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- LA Times Ideas, February 1993 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Macro Model Working Conference, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Bowles, Weisskopf, Gordon Policy Papers, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Comparing Jackson's Economic Program To Those Of Other Candidates in 1988, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Notes Related to Jackson's Budget Plan And Economics Program, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Clinton program: Coalition For Democatic Values (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Democracy and Macroeconomy, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- NSF Policy, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Details Regarding Macro Model Working Conference, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Papers Related To Macarthur Economics, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Papers Related To Boston Association For Evolutionary Economics, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Papers Related To URPE At ASSA Session, New Orleans, January 1992 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Model Comparison Seminar, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Economics Dept. Course Evaluation, 1994,1995 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Papers Related To Journalists At Macarthur Foundation, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Foundations And Economics, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  Includes a Paper By Paul Mahlerbe
- Various Recommendation Letters, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Course Load, 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 54)
- Dissertation related papers (Box 7, Folder 55)
- Committee On Political Economy Curriculum, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Papers related to search for a new faculty member at New School, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 58)
- Who's Who?, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 59)
- Papers related to Swedish Conference, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 60)
- Wider volume (Box 7, Folder 62)
- Papers related to Brussels colloquium, January 1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Seminar On: "The Political Economy Of Advanced Industrial Societies", December 1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Various Articles By Gordon (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Employment And Labor Statistics (Box 8, Folder 10)
- OEO Labor Market Research Statistics, April 1971 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- EFI Metrics papers, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Materials Related To University Of Siena, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Materials related to Model Simulation (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Materials related to Model Simulation (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Miscellanous Notes (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Miscellanous Letters, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Papers related to Dynamic Models (Box 8, Folder 22)
- NYU Paper on Macro Model Seminar, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Institute for Policy Studies Papers, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Worker Representation And Participation Survey, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 26)